Paul Schneider

School of Health and Related Research The University of Sheffield West Court, Mappin Street S1 4DT, Sheffield, UK p.schneider@sheffield.ac.uk Skype: 42cee0f7bf398de Web: Academic profile Orcid: 0000-0003-3552-1087

SUMMARY

Boundlessly curious PhD student, combining a background in medicine with strong technical research skills and a solid foundation in economic evaluation and data science. Passionate about working across disciplines to inform evidence-based decision-making in health policy.

EDUCATION

Wellcome Trust PhD in Public Health, Economics, and Decision Science

09/2018-08/2022

School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), University of Sheffield, England, UK

Thesis: Social tariffs, preference heterogeneity, and collective choice.

Supervisors: Prof. John Brazier, Prof. Ben van Hout

MSc in Health Sciences Research (with distinction)

09/2016-08/2018

Faculty of Health, Medicine and Life Sciences, Maastricht University, the Netherlands

Emphasis on epidemiology and quantitative research methodology. Specialisation in Health

Technology Assessment. Supervisor: Prof. Manuela Joore

Doctoral Degree in Medicine (with distinction)

09/2013-10/2017

Institute for Health Systems Research, Witten/Herdecke University, Germany

Thesis: Association between nurse and physician staffing and the quality of care in German hospital. Supervisor: Prof. Max Geraedts.

Medical Doctor 04/2009–12/2015

Witten/Herdecke University, Germany

International clinical electives in Ghana, Namibia, South Africa and Barbados.

EXPERIENCE

Independent Research Project

03/2017-08/2018

Netherlands Institute of Health Service Research (NIVEL), Utrecht, the Netherlands

Initiated and led a project using method of digital epidemiology to monitor the incidence of influenza in the Netherlands in real-time, using search queries and statistical learning methods (Lasso Regression in combination with cross-validation for time series).

Research Internship 09/2017–08/2018

Maastricht University Medical Center, the Netherlands

Investigated the variability of costs of breast cancer between patients and within patients over time, using group-based trajectory modeling and clinical real-world data.

Independent Internship

04/2016-07/2016

World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland

Collected and verified content and data for the WHO, OECD and World Bank joint report on 'Delivering quality health services'. Supervisor: Dr. Sepideh Bagheri Nejad.

Paul Schneider

SKILLS

Most experienced: R/R Studio, Markdown, Shiny, Open Research Some experience: Leaflet, LaTex, Java, Python, Shiny Server, Git, Github, Hugo

LANGUAGES

English (fluent), German (native), Dutch (working knowledge), French (basic)

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

Schneider PP, Geraedts M. Staffing and the incidence of pressure ulcers in German hospitals: A multicenter cross-sectional study. Nursing Health Sciences. 2016. https://dx.doi.org/10.1111/nhs.12292; Open Access version: https://dx.doi.org/10.1111/nhs.12292; Open Access version: https://dx.doi.org/10.1111/nhs.12292; Open Access version: https://dx.doi.org/10.4126/FRL01-006402986

OTHER PUBLICATIONS AND WORK SAMPLES

- **Working paper:** Schneider PP. Social tariffs and democratic choice do population-based health state values reflect the will of the people? Available at: https://bitowaqr.github.io/about_me/files/c1.pdf
- **Preprint:** Schneider PP, Smith RA, Bullas AM, Bayley T, Haake SSJ, Brennan A, Goyder E. Where should new parkrun events be located? Modelling the potential impact of 200 new events on socio-economic inequalities in access and participation. MedRxiv. 2019. doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/19004143
- Website: Schneider PP, Smith RA, Bullas AM, Bayley T, Haake SSJ, Brennan A, Goyder E. Identifying Optimal Locations for Maximising Access to parkun Interactive online map. 2019. Available at: https://iohnap.shinyapps.io/parkrun/
- **Website**: Schneider PP, Smith R, Brennan A, Goyder E. Parkrun: Who has access, and who participates? Analysis and policy recommendations. 2018. Available at: https://bitowaqr.github.io/
- **Preprint:** Schneider PP, van Gool CJ, Spreeuwenberg P, Hooiveld M, Donker GA, Barnett DJ, Paget J. Using digital epidemiology methods to monitor influenza-like illness in the Netherlands in real-time: the 2017-2018 season. bioRxiv. 2018. doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/440867
- Tutorial: Schneider PP, Paget J, Spreeuwenberg P, Barnett D, van Gool C. Using Wikipedia and Google data to estimate near real-time influenza incidence in Germany: A Tutorial in R [Preprint]. 2017. Available at: https://projectflutrend.github.io/
- **Thesis**: Schneider PP. Association between nurse and physician staffing and the quality of care in German hospitals [in German]. 2017. Available at: https://doi.org/10.4126/FRL01-006405375
- **Poster presentation**: Schneider PP, Kraska R, Geraedts M. Staffing and pressure ulcer prevention in hospitals [in German]. 59th Congress of the Society of Social Medicine and Prevention (DGSMP). 2016. Poster available at: https://goo.gl/9G5HEz; Abstract available at: https://dx.doi.org/10.1055/s-0036-1586694